# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I'm going to share a homestyle dish with you.
# 大盘土鸡
Large Plate Chicken
# 首先我们选择雄赳赳气昂昂的土公鸡一只（6斤左右）
First let's choose a "majestic" free range rooster (about 6 jin, 3kg)
# 没有土公鸡的同学也可以用普通的商品鸡代替
Students who don't have a free-range rooster can also use broiler chicken instead.
# 首先我们取下鸡的头脚
First we chop the head and feet off the chicken.
# 然后再从背部打开之后去除内脏清洗干净备用
Then open it from the back, remove the guts and clean it.
# 清洗干净之后取出鸡脖子里面的淋巴和气管
After cleaning, remove the lymphatic and tracheal tubes from the chicken's neck.
# 同学们禽类的淋巴一般都集中在脖子和尾部
The lymphatic system of birds is usually concentrated in the neck and tail.
# 由于土鸡长得黑
Because this free-range chicken is black.
# 所以黑色的淋巴也是正常现象
That's why the black lymph is normal.
# 对于这一部位必须仔细处理
This area must be treated carefully.
# 然后剁掉鸡的脚趾甲再剁成大小均匀的块
Then chop off the chicken's toenails and chop them into even-sized pieces.
# 鸡肉可以适量的剁大块一些方便大口吃肉
The chicken can be chopped into large pieces to make it easier to eat the meat.
# 下一步开始处理鸡肉
Start the chicken cleaning process.
# 首先我们把鸡肉放入盆中
First, we put the chicken in a pot.
# 加入适量的淘米水反复抓洗几遍
Add the some rice washing water and scrub several times.
# 这样的目的是去除鸡肉中残留的血水和鸡腥味
This is to remove any residual blood and gamey taste from the chicken.
# 当然嫌麻烦的同学也可以直接将鸡肉焯水
You can also parboil the chicken if you couldn't find rice washing water.
# 鸡肉清洗干净之后捞出挤干水分备用
Drain the chicken after cleaning.
# 下一步开始腌制
Next, start marinating.
# 首先我们在鸡肉中加入适量的食用盐（约3克}
First we add a good amount of table salt to the chicken (about 3 grams)
# 然后搅拌1分钟码味
Then mix for a minute.
# 最后再加入适量的淀粉拌匀
Then, add some starch and mix well
# 加淀粉的目的是防止鸡肉受热时水份蒸发变老
The purpose of adding starch is to prevent the moisture from evaporating when the chicken is heated.
# 同学们普通的嫩鸡则不需要添加
Skip the starch if using broiler chicken
# 下一步开始准备香料水
Next, start preparing the spice water.
# 碗中加入八角两颗
Add two star anise to the bowl
# 加入适量的桂皮
Add a piece of cinnamon
# 加入适量的青花椒和红花椒
Add a generous amount of green and red Sichuan peppercorns
# 加入去籽的草果一颗
Add one tsao-ko with seeds removed
# 加入白芷一小块
Add a small piece of baizhi
# 加入适量的良姜
Add some galangal
# 加入香叶一片
Add one bay leaf.
# 加入少许的白胡椒
Add a bit of ground white pepper
# 加入小茴香一小把
Add a handful of fennel seeds.
# 加入适量的清水淘洗浸泡五分钟
Add the appropriate amount of water and soak for five minutes.
# 然后准备适量的子弹头干辣椒
Then prepare a generous amount of dried "Zidantou" chili pepper.
# 剪掉头尾再浸泡五分钟备用
Cut off the heads and tails and soak for five minutes.
# 剪掉头尾的目的是挤压出多余的辣椒籽
The purpose of cutting off the ends is to squeeze out the excess chili seeds.
# 然后挤干水分捞出备用
Then drain and squeeze out the water.
# 五分钟之后倒出泡好的香料用纱布包好
After five minutes, pour out the soaked spices and wrap them in a cheesecloth.
# 然后放入盆中加入滚烫的开水浸泡焖凉备用
Then put it in a pot of boiling water and let it soak to cool.
# 这一步的目的是取其香料水
The purpose of this step is to making the spice water
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Start preparing the other ingredients next.
# 准备黄皮土豆三个
Prepare three yellow-skinned potatoes
# 去皮之后切成滚刀块备用
Peel and cut into large pieces
# 准备几个青红椒切成小块备用
Prepare a few green and red peppers cut into small chunks
# 准备大葱两根切成颗粒备用
Prepare two spring onions, chopped into small pieces.
# 准备适量的大蒜拍散备用
Crush a generous amount of garlic
# 准备几块生姜拍散之后切成大颗粒备用
Prepare a few pieces of ginger and chop them into large pieces.
# 准备洋葱一个对半切开之后切成小片备用
Prepare an onion and cut it in half, then slice it into small pieces.
# 同学们洋葱也可以放入碗中像这样晃开
You can put the chopped onions in a bowl and shake them like this.
# 辅料准备好之后下一步开始调酱油汁
Once the ingredients are ready, the next step is to make the sauce.
# 碗中加入生抽酱油40克
Add 40g of soy sauce in a bowl
# 加入蚝油30克搅拌均匀备用
Add 30 grams of oyster sauce and mix well.
# 最后准备土冰糖一小块敲散备用
Finally, crush a small piece of rock sugar.
# 同学们相对于白糖来说土冰糖成菜会更香
Rock sugar tastes better when compared to normal sugar for this dish.
# 下一步开始制作
Let's cook the dish.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, let's heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入略多的底油
When the wok is hot, add a little more base oil.
# 油温四成之后加入准备好的土冰糖小火炒化
When the oil temperature reaches 40% (120°C), add the prepared sugar and fry on low heat.
# 炒至冰糖融化起泡即可
Stir-fry until the sugar melts and bubbles.
# 冰糖起泡之后将准备好的土鸡块下锅翻炒几分钟
Once the sugar is bubbling, stir-fry the prepared chicken pieces for a few minutes.
# 这一步是将鸡块的皮收紧
This step is to tighten the chicken skin.
# 炒香炒至上色
Stir-fry until the color comes out.
# 鸡肉炒香上色吐油之后开始下料
When the chicken spit out the oil, then start to add other ingredients.
# 加入准备好的姜葱粒和泡好的干辣椒
Add the prepared diced ginger, onion and the soaked dried chillies
# 然后继续中小火翻炒一分钟
Then continue to sauté on medium-low heat for another minute.
# 中途再加入少许的老抽固色
Add a little more dark soy sauce to adjust the color.
# 上好色之后加入一半的大葱翻炒断生
Once color is good, add half of the spring onions and stir-fry.
# 大葱炒至断生之后加入焖凉的香料水
Stir-fry the spring onions until they are half cooked, then add the spice water.
# 再加入调好的酱油
And then add the sauce.
# 然后大火烧开之后转中火烧15分钟
Then bring to boil over high heat and then cook for 15 minutes on medium heat.
# 同学们也可以从这里开始用高压锅压6分钟
You can also use pressure cooker to cook for 6 minutes.
# 如果采用高压锅压 则需要减少一倍的香料水
If you use pressure cooker, you'll only need half of the spice water.
# 15分钟之后加入切好的土豆块
After 15 minutes add the potato pieces.
# 再加入适量的葱油
Add some more scallion oil.
# 加葱油的目的是防止土豆煮软之后糊汤
The purpose of the scallion oil is to prevent the potato starch from thickening the broth too much.
# 然后继续烧15分钟
Then continue cooking for another 15 minutes.
# 中途根据口味加入适量的盐调咸味
Add salt in the process to adjust the taste.
# 15分钟之后加入剩余的大葱和青红椒烧至断生
After 15 minutes, add the remaining spring onions and peppers and cook until half cook.
# 最后加入切好的洋葱块烧几秒钟
Finally, add the chopped onions and cook for a few seconds.
# 烧洋葱的时候需要加入适量的明油亮汤
After adding the onions, add some scallion oil to brighten the dish.
# 亮汤之后即可出锅装在有面皮的大盘中
When the dish is ready, serve on a large plate with some noodles.
# 一道非常美味的大盘土鸡就制作完成
A very tasty Large Plate free-range Chicken is ready!
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一原料最好选择五个月6斤左右的黑公鸡
First, it's better to choose a five-month-old and around six jin (3kg) black rooster.
# 此鸡肉质比普通鸡略老但肉更香
This chicken is a little older than normal but has a better meat flavor.
# 只需要在鸡肉中加入适量的淀粉拌匀
Add some starch to the chicken pieces and mix well.
# 这样既可保证和普通鸡一样嫩
This way you can keep it as tender as normal chicken.
# 第二
Second,
# 平时不用的淘米水也可以用来清洗鸡肉
Rice washing water can be used to clean the chicken.
# 这样可以较好地去除鸡肉中的血腥味
This will better remove the gamey taste from the chicken.
# 第三商用版本可以将土豆冷油下锅炸熟再烧
Third, for commercial use, you can deep fry bulk amount of potatoes in cold oil before cooking them.
# 这样可以有效缩短烧制的时间
This effectively reduces the cooking time.
# 也能解决成品浑汤的缺点
It also solves the disadvantage of a cloudy soup.
# 当然家庭制作可以不考虑这一步
Of course, home cooking can be done without this step.
# 第四
Fourth,
# 下面开始分享商业版面皮子的做法
Here's how to make the flat noodles
# 首先我们在盆中加入清水300克
First, add 300 grams of water to a bowl.
# 加入食用盐10克搅拌化开
Add 10g of table salt and stir to dissolve
# 然后加入高筋面粉500克
Then add 500g of high gluten flour
# 充分拌匀揉捏成团状
Mix well and knead well to form a ball
# 如果商用则需要提前制作成半成品
If for commercial use, semi-finished products must be made in advance
# 同学们切记1斤面粉6两水10克盐
1 jin (0.5kg) of flour, 0.6 jin (0.3kg) of water and 10 grams of salt.
# 水不能太多也不能太少
Not too much and not too little water.
# 否则面皮没有弹性
Otherwise the dough has no elasticity.
# 家庭制作嫌麻烦可以直接选用挂面
If you don't want to make it at home, you can just use dried noodles.
# 揉成团之后封上保鲜膜醒发25分钟（夏天）
Knead the dough and then cover with plastic wrap and let it sit for 25 minutes (summer)
# 25分钟之后在砧板上涂抹上适量的油
After 25 minutes, grease the cutting board with a generous amount of oil
# 然后将面团按照此拳法挤压对折5分钟
Then squeeze and fold the dough for 5 minutes according to this technique.
# 5分钟之后再继续醒面20分钟
After 5 minutes, continue to rise for another 20 minutes.
# 20分钟之后取出面团涂上适量的植物油防止粘手
After 20 minutes remove the dough and coat with a generous amount of vegetable oil to prevent sticking.
# 继续用按摩的手法挤压成长长的面团
Continue to squeeze into a long dough with massaging strokes
# 然后再抹上适量的油捏断分成小块
Then spread some oil on it and break it into small pieces.
# 最后再搓成小条放入盘中
Finally, roll it into small strips and place it on a plate.
# 再次抹上适量的油封存10分钟之后即可随取随用
Apply some oil again and seal for 10 minutes before serving.
# 第五
Fifth,
# 面皮下锅前的处理
Making the noodle before cooking
# 首先在砧板上抹上一层食用油
Start by rubbing a layer of oil on a cutting board
# 然后取下一小块面皮推拉涂抹成薄片即可使用
Then put a strip of dough and push and pull to spread into a thin sheet.
# 菜板上面多余的油不洗则不浪费
Excess oil on the cutting board is not wasted if you don't wash it.
# 普通家庭就当做是菜板保养的损耗
You can use it as the maintenance of the cutting board.
# 面皮制作完成之后直接下锅煮至断生即可
After the flat noodle is made, cook it directly in a pot.
# 同学们也可以不用煮的太熟
You shouldn't overcook them.
# 否则不够嚼劲弹牙
Otherwise, it's not chewy enough.
# 煮至断生之后即可捞出
Cook until it's half cooked and then remove from the water
# 然后放入凉开水中凉透即可装盘垫底
Then put them into cold water to cool them down before serving.
# 最后即可享受勤劳带来的美味
At the end, you can enjoy the delicious tasty dish of hard work.